John Pritchard

jdp@syntelos.com

Interactive Server Side in Java

Internet Scale systems, products and applications -- large and small.

Technology Strategy, Design and Implementation on "can't be beat" schedules with "can't be beat" usability and performance. (To beat this would cost many times more). Experience, skill, talent.

Large Scale with Amazon EC2, S3.

Programming Language design and implementation, Systems design and implementation, Performance problems diagnosis and repair, Application Security analysis and design.

Work Experience

<u>Principal Engineer, Syntelos Commercial Network Services</u> 5/2006 - Present

- Application and product development consulting.
- Syntelos is in development to deliver online tools for the construction of Internet Scale Network Automatons as for Google Desktop, Facebook, Netvibes, Mashups or any other site. A network automaton provides server side processing for client side widgets in HTML / AJAX, Java or Flash.
- Consulting services for server side and lightweight client side applications in Java.

Executive Director Product Development, Ecensity 12/2001 - 5/2006

• Designed and implemented the product of this software house originating from Paris, France. The product for enterprise web application composition, management and personalization online in the browser demanded a degree of flexibility that was impossible to achieve using conventional technologies. Responding to experience and demand, a platform for the development of the product was designed to solve all problems in online capabilities. The platform and product were completed on schedule, and the company was subsequently acquired. See An XVM named Edo6.

Field Application Engineer, SilverStream Software 10/1998 - 1/2001

 Addressing hard problems and performance issues for consulting clients, application security and risk analyses, application and component development.

Systems Developer, Datek Online 8/1996 - 9/1998

• Designed and developed the first real time stream stock quote service, the Datek Streamer. Implemented, maintained and supported the Streamer Client Applet Beta for 15,000 customers. Identified the technique for streaming to clients with and without firewalls.

Education

Columbia University, Economics, New York, NY

12/1990 - 6/1996

- Major in Economics with Computer Science
- Five years' coursework completed

George Washington University, Mech E, Washington, DC

1/1985 - 6/1986

· One years' coursework completed

Highlights in technical skills

Java, HTTP, XML, Web Services, and so much more.

Some publications

Representational State Programming

An architectural approach building on the principles of Fielding's REST to maximize scalability and flexbility.

gnu.iou

Library package for implementing open source server side products. <u>Efficient hyperlink maintenance for HTTP</u>

A thought experiment into dynamic, network wide maintenance of links as in hypertext.

Professional

Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)

Monster Resume-ID 102480718

Linked/in/syntelos